Helle collection of Plath family photographs, 1910-1963
Mortimer Rare Book Room
- SERIES II. Photographs of Sylvia Plath and her family
  - Anonymous. Plath family home, Wellesley, Massachusetts[?September 1948], Black and white photograph with deckle edges. 13 x 9 cm.; Drawing of the floor plan of the interior by Aurelia Schober Plath on verso: Note: Car is not mine! Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath's home. Stamped on verso: G625 Subject: Plath family residence at 26 Elmwood Road, Wellesley, Massachusetts. Unidentified man and car in the front yard. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 42)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Sylvia PlathSeptember 1948, Black and white photograph with deckle edges. 13 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Sylvia and Warren, Sept. 1948 / They both join me in wishing Aunt Frieda and Uncle Walter a Merry Christmas and Happy New Year. Stamped on verso: 058A Subject: Three quarter view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) sitting on the lawn at their home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. Warren is wearing a suit and tie while Sylvia is wearing a checked dress © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 43)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Aurelia Schober Plath, May 1949., Black and white photograph. 9 x 13 cm.; Typed caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: May, 1949 / Warren Plath, age 14 / 5'11" Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Warren and Aurelia Plath Stamped on verso: Z96 Subject: Three quarter view of Warren Plath (1935- ) wearing a band uniform and Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994) in a checked jacket sitting in the yard at home in Wellesley, Massachusetts © Estate of Aurelia Greenwood Schober (Helle 44)
  - Anonymous. Aurelia flanked by Sylvia and Warren PlathSeptember 1949, Black and white photograph. 9 x 13 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Sept. 1949 / Sylvia-almost 17 / Warren - [almost] 14½. Taken in the rear of our house. This does not do either Sylvia or Warren justice, but is excellent of me. So-here's to the expansion of my own ego as I send this to you. Stamped on verso: 568 Subject: Full view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963), Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994), and Warren Plath (1935- ) in the yard at their home in Wellesley. All are wearing suits. © Estate of Aurelia Greenwood Schober (Helle 45)
  - Studio portrait of Sylvia Plath 1950, Black and white photograph. 10 x 14 cm.; Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath Subject: Head and shoulders view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963). According to Letters Home (page 47), this was Plath's high school graduation portrait. © Estate of Sylvia Plath (Helle 46)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath, September 1950., Black and white photograph. 9 x 13 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Sylvia Sept. 1950 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath - almost 18. Stamped on verso: 642S Kodak Velox Paper Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) sitting on the front stair at her home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. Plath is wearing a suit and hat. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 47)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath, January 1951, Black and white photograph. 7.5 x 9.5 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Sylvia Jan. 1951 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath Age 18 Stamped on verso: Kodak Velox Paper Subject: Head and shoulders view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) sitting on the front stair at her home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. She is wearing a zippered jacket. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 48)
  - Studio portrait of Sylvia PlathNovember 1952, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Sylvia Plath / November 1952. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Age 20 Subject: Head portrait of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) wearing a necklace. © Estate of Sylvia Plath (Helle 49)
  - Anonymous. Greeting card with photograph of Wellesley house in the snow[?1954], Black and white. 14 x 10.7 cm.(card); 7 x 7 cm. (photograph); Caption on recto by Aurelia Schober Plath: Our Home Caption on recto by Aurelia below Greetings: from / Aunt Aurelia Subject: Partial front view of the Plath family home at 26 Elmwood Road, Wellesley, Massachusetts. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 50)
  - Anonymous. Christmas card with photograph of Warren and Sylvia Plath1955, Black and white. 214 x 10.7 cm. (card); 5 x 7.5 cm.(photograph); Caption on recto under photograph by Aurelia Schober Plath: Warren and Sylvia 9/55 Inscription on recto under greeting Merry Christmas 1955: to June, Glenn and Anita / Aunt Aurelia Subject: Full view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) standing in the yard at Wellesley, Massachusetts, September 1955. Sylvia is wearing a suit and black tam © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 51)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath, September 111955, Black and white photograph. 9 x 13 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Sylvia, Sept. 11, 1955 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath - almost 23 years old Stamped on verso: Kodak Velox Paper Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) standing in the front yard of her home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. She is wearing a black tam, patterned jersey, dark skirt, and holds a handbag. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 52)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Aurelia Plath in front of a Christmas treeDecember 31, 1955, Black and white photograph. 9 x 13 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Schober Plath: Warren Aurelia Caption on verso by Aurelia: Warren and Aurelia, December 31, 1955 / Wellesley, Massachusetts. Stamped on verso: Kodak Velox Paper Subject: Nearly full view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994) sitting on the floor in front of a Christmas tree. Warren is wearing a jacket and tie. © Unknown (Helle 53)
  - Anonymous (?Ted Hughes). Warren and Sylvia Plath, Paris, August 1956., Black and white photograph. 9 x 13 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Schober Plath: Warren and Sylvia, Paris, 1956. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Warren & Sylvia Plath / Sylvia is almost 24. Stamped on verso: Kodak Velox Paper Subject: Head and shoulder view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) in Paris. © Estate of Ted Hughes (Helle 54)
  - Ted Hughes. Aurelia Schober PlathSeptember 1958, Black and white photograph. 4.5 x 7.5 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: I was the only one who looked natural in this snap taken by my son-in-law in September '58. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Aurelia Plath - Taken by Ted Hughes Subject: Full view of Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994) standing on the front stairs of her home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. Photograph has been trimmed. Sylvia Plath's left hand and handbag are still visible. © Estate of Ted Hughes (Helle 55)
  - Anonymous (?Ted Hughes). Sylvia Plath and baby Frieda1960, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 6.5 cm.; Caption on verso by Sylvia Plath: Frieda & me - she in her lacy white dress you sent - doesn't it look sweet on her? Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath and baby Frieda Stamped on verso: C670 Kodak Vellox Paper Subject: Side view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and Frieda Rebecca Hughes (1960- ). Plath's hair is in a ponytail. © Estate of Ted Hughes (Helle 56)
  - Anonymous (?Ted Hughes). Sylvia Plath and baby FriedaJanuary 1961, Black and white photograph. 6.2 x 6.4 cm.; Caption on verso by Sylvia Plath: Frieda Rebecca age 9 months / plus her mother & / her teddy bear Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath and daughter Frieda Stamped on verso Kodak Velox Paper Subject: Head and shoulders view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) holding Frieda Rebecca Hughes (1960- ) on her lap. Plath's hair is in braids on her head and Frieda is holding a teddy bear. © Estate of Ted Hughes (Helle 57)
  - Anonymous. Aurelia PlathJanuary 1961, Color photograph. 9 x 14.7 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Aurelia Plath, January 1961. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: At Cape Cod Stamped on verso: This is a Kodacolor Print Made by Kodak / April 1961 Subject: Full view of Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994) at Cape Cod in the winter sitting on a porch. © Unknown (Helle 58)
  - Anonymous. Aurelia Plath August 1963, Color photograph. 9 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Informal (!) snap taken at Denis, Cape Cod - Aug 1963 / Aunt Aurelia Stamped on verso: Kodak Paper Subject: Three-quarter view of Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994) at Cape Cod in the summer sitting on a lawn chair. Pen markings cover up her knees. © Unknown (Helle 59)
- SERIES III. Other photographs
  - Carte Postale of Berck-Plage-L'Hôpital Vincentn.d (Helle 60)